# **Justin Horein**

Portland, OR | 608.209.3927 | justinhorein@gmail.com | justinhorein.com | github.com/justinhorein | linkedin.com/in/justinhorein

## **PROFILE**

Hard working and creative individual, interested in helping people through software development. A recent graduate of the Tech Academy, I am now equipped with experience in a variety of programming technologies. In working through the Tech Academy's 900 hour plus curriculum, including 2 Live Team Projects, I have demonstrated the ability to learn a lot in a short period of time.

## **EXPERIENCE**

- Python Django Live Project: Worked on a Python/Django web app as an intern for Prosper IT Consulting. Utilizing a Movie Database API, I constructed a page that allows users to search movie titles and view the results list in a presentable format (Bootstrap Cards). Additionally, I made a page where users can store titles they've already viewed (utilizing a model and database). Along the way, I participated in a series of standup meetings in practice of the Agile/Scrum methodology and practiced responsible version control procedures.

View code here: <a href="https://github.com/justinhorein/Python Django Live Project">https://github.com/justinhorein/Python Django Live Project</a>

C Sharp Live Project: Another internship I did with Prosper IT Consulting, in which I contributed to the ongoing development of a website for Theater Vertigo in SE Portland. Most of my effort was spent styling 5 pages for the Ticket Management section of the website. I gained a lot of experience working with CSS and Bootstrap in particular. I also completed another story that involved making a tiny fix to the back-end. Like the Python Project, this project was structured as a sprint in practice of the Agile/Scrum methodology.

Couldn't get the code, but you can read an in-depth summary here:

<a href="https://github.com/justinhorein/C">https://github.com/justinhorein/C</a> Sharp Live Project/blob/master/C%23%20LP%20Summary .pdf

C Sharp Black Jack: This is a console app, I built, as a one-player game of Black Jack. On this project, I gained a lot of experience coding in the Object Oriented Programming Paradigm. I learned how to organize my code in a library, as well as utilize concepts like Polymorphism, Inheritance, Interfaces, Encapsulation and Abstract Classes.

View code here: <a href="https://github.com/justinhorein/C Sharp Black Jack">https://github.com/justinhorein/C Sharp Black Jack</a>

RGB Color Picker: This is a browser app, I built, as an interactive game for testing a user's skills in identifying RGB Color Codes. While building this app, I learned how to select and configure DOM elements as well as write code in the functional programming paradigm.

View code here: <a href="https://github.com/justinhorein/RGB-Color-Picker">https://github.com/justinhorein/RGB-Color-Picker</a>

- **Tic-Tac-Toe:** This is a browser app that allows users to play the classic game of Tic-Tac-Toe. While building this app, I got even more practice with functional programming and interacting with the DOM.

View code here: <a href="https://github.com/justinhorein/Tic-Tac-Toe">https://github.com/justinhorein/Tic-Tac-Toe</a>

Calculator: This is a browser app that functions as a basic add, subtract, multiply and divide Calculator. In writing this app, I got my feet wet with Arrow Functions as well as Event Listeners. As well as, ofcourse, getting more practice with functional programming and interacting with the DOM.

View code here: <a href="https://github.com/justinhorein/Calculator">https://github.com/justinhorein/Calculator</a>

## **SKILLS**

- LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Python, C#.
- **FRAMEWORKS:** Django, .Net, Express, Entity.
- **LIBRARIES:** Bootstrap, jQuery.
- **DATABASES:** SQL SERVER, SQLite.
- **IDE:** Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook.

## **EDUCATION**

- The Tech Academy

Coding School Portland, OR

## Software Developer Certificate

Sept 2019 - May 2020

 Intensive developer training, over 900 hours of study content and drills. Studied Computer Science Fundamentals, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Relational Databases, C# w/.NET framework, Python w/ Django framework, Object Oriented Programming, MVC, Agile/Scrum, Version Control and more.

#### Pyramind

Music Production School San Francisco, CA

#### **Complete Producer Program**

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

## - Madison College

College Madison, WI

#### English

Jan 2014 - Aug 2014

## **WORK HISTORY**

#### - Intern

Prosper IT Consulting | Portland, OR | (503) 206-6915 January 6 - 19, 2020. Also, March 16 - 29, 2020.

 Helped develop a website for a Local Theater Company. Also, developed a web app for keeping track of a movie collection. Both projects were 2 week sprints structured in the Scrum methodology (read more on my GitHub).

#### - Pizzaioli

Pizza Pi Vegan | Seattle, WA | (206) 343-1415 February 2019 - July 2019

## - Recording Engineer

Word Arts | Seattle, WA | (206) 353-4844 March 1 - March 31, 2019. Also, November 19 - 30, 2019.

 Recorded a glass strings trio for an art installation. Also, recorded a guitar piece for a commercial.

#### - Deli

Bert's Red Apple | Seattle, WA | (206) 322-1330 March 2018 - February 2019

#### Shift Leader

Capriotti's Sandwich Shop | Madison, WI | Since Closed Down April 2016 - December 2016

• Led a team of sandwich artisans to fulfill customer orders and maintain the restaurant.

## Counter

Milio's Sandwiches | Madison, WI (Regent St.) | (608) 233-3233 March 2015 - April 2016

## **INDEPENDENT STUDY**

- Working on *UDEMY* Course, "The Web Developer Bootcamp" by Colt Steele.

View code here: <a href="https://github.com/justinhorein/Web-Dev-Bootcamp-by-Colt-Steele">https://github.com/justinhorein/Web-Dev-Bootcamp-by-Colt-Steele</a>